(
"ai_sub_version": "2.5.0",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 2,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 12,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "gemini-cli:gemini-3-flash-preview",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.1-flash-lite-preview",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"web_search_tool": "duckduckgo",
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true
),
"gemini_cli": (
"timeout": 600,
"overwrite_system_prompt": false
)
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": true,
"fps": 1,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": "libx264"
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"run": 3,
"max": 9,
"delay": 30
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false
)
目指せよ快眠
Aim for a good sleep
勝ち取れ安眠
Win a good sleep
いざ夢の世界へ
Let's go to the world of dreams
理想の眠りを
Seeking the ideal...
求めて
...ideal sleep
さあ
Come now
始めよう
Let's start
おやすみ
Good night
ノンレム睡眠レム睡眠
Non-REM sleep, REM sleep
私は囚われの姫
I am a captured princess
魔王の城の中で
Inside the Demon King's castle
独り閉じ込められては
Being trapped alone,
毎日ひたすらに眠ってます
I sleep intently every day
今宵も 布団に入り
Tonight too, getting into my futon
スヤスヤリスト生活
Sleepy princess life
枕も
My pillow...
シーツも
...and sheets
硬くて眠れない
Are too hard, I can't sleep
(君も寝具にしてやろうか！)
(Shall I make you into bedding too!)
目指せよ快眠
Aim for a good sleep
勝ち取れ安眠
Win a good sleep
いざ夢の世界へ
Let's go to the world of dreams
ふかふかの枕
With a fluffy pillow
手に入れて
that I've obtained,
この疲れ 癒したい
I want to heal this fatigue
恐れず前進
Move forward without fear,
ほぐせよ全身
relax your whole body
瞼を閉じたなら
Once you close your eyes,
すべすべのシーツの上で
on top of smooth sheets
さあ
Come now,
始めよう
let's start
おやすみ
Good night
ノンレム睡眠レム睡眠
Non-REM sleep, REM sleep
私は囚われの姫
I am a captured princess
悲鳴が響く夜に
In the night where screams echo,
独りで檻を抜け出し
escaping the cage all alone,
今日もお散歩へと行ってきます
I'm going for a walk again today
幾多の試練を越えて
Overcoming many trials,
新たな寝具を求めて
seeking new bedding
もっと
More...
マグマで
Even with magma,
猛毒で
even with deadly poison,
死んでも 眠りたい
I want to sleep, even if I die.
「城ごと寝具にしてやろうか！」
"Shall I turn the whole castle into bedding?!"
掴めよ快眠
Seize that deep sleep!
疲れて安眠
Restful sleep after exhaustion!
いざ夢の向こうへ
Now, to the other side of dreams!
ハイテク目覚まし
With a high-tech alarm clock
手に入れて
in my hands,
気持ちよく目覚めたい
I want to wake up feeling refreshed!
まだまだ前進
Still moving forward,
華麗に変身
a magnificent transformation!
ごはんを食べたなら
Once I've had my meal,
魔法のベッドにダイブして
I'll dive into my magic bed.
さあ 始めよう
Now, let's begin...
おやすみ
Good night.
明日はもっと 今日よりずっと
Tomorrow, even more than today...
いい夢見れるかな
I wonder if I'll have a good dream.
ふわふわの羽根に包まれて
Wrapped in fluffy feathers,
ココロゆくまで眠りたい
I want to sleep to my heart's content.
目指せよ快眠
Aim for that deep sleep!
勝ち取れ安眠
Seize that restful sleep!
いざ夢の世界へ
Now, to the world of dreams!
理想の眠りを求めて
Searching for the ideal slumber,
さあ 始めよう
now, let's begin...
おやすみ
Good night.
もう あと5分
Just five more minutes...
おやすみ
Good night.
ノンレム睡眠 レム睡眠
Non-REM sleep, REM sleep...
スヤァ
*Zzz*
うーーん！
Mmmgh...!
はい！こんまっする！ホロライブ3期生の白銀ノエルでーす！
Alright! Konmuscle! I'm Shirogane Noel from Hololive Gen 3!
本日はライブに来てくれてありがとう！
Thank you all for coming to the live today!
そして、ハッシュタグはこちら！#白銀ノエル生誕祭2025 たくさんスクショして、SNSに投稿してください！
And here's the hashtag! #ShiroganeNoelBirthday2025. Take lots of screenshots and post them on social media!
今日のライブのテーマなんですが、見ての通りね、睡眠、安眠、癒やしライブとなっております。
The theme for today's live, as you can see, is sleep, restful sleep, and healing.
ライブ後半にかけて盛り上がっていくので、ぜひ皆様も盛り上がってください！
It's going to get more exciting toward the second half, so please enjoy it everyone!
てな感じで、1曲目は『快眠！安眠！スヤリスト生活』を歌わせていただきました。
So, for the first song, I performed 'Kaimin! Anmin! Syalist Seikatsu'.
あの曲中のね、団長踊りながら、ま、変身したシーンがありましたけど、
During that song, there was a scene where I transformed while dancing,
わかった？わかったっていうか、みんな気づいてる？てか、おメイクがちょっと変わりましたー！
did you see it? I mean, did everyone notice? My makeup has changed slightly!
お気づきでしょうか？
Did you catch that?
ま、具体的にね、どういうところが改善されたかと言いますと、あの、髪の毛がですね、あの、サラサラによりなりました。
To be specific about what's improved... my hair is now much silkier.
ええ、サラサラになって、特に後ろとかね、わかるかな、ほら、サラサラーー！
Yes, it's so silky. Especially from the back, can you tell? Look, so silky!
もう本当に、いつでも、あの、シャンプーのCM待ってます、てな感じでサラサラになったののと、
Seriously, I'm ready for a shampoo commercial anytime. It's that silky now.
あとおメイクもね、ちょっと変わっております。ま、いろんなね、表情ができるようになったんですけど、
Also, my makeup is a bit different. I can make a wider range of expressions now.
えっと、なんか、なんかリスナーのいちゃんが怒るようなこと言ってるって、
Wait, it seems some listeners are saying something that would make me mad...
おんおん。え、何？お前、ちょっと太った？
Oh? What's that? "Did you get a bit chubby?"
んんー！何？！太ってないよ！最近ダイエット頑張ってるもん！
Ngh! What?! I haven't! I've been working hard on my diet lately!
てな感じで、前はちょっと結構ガチ怒りって感じだったんですけど、マイルド怒りになりました。はい。
So, while before it was a serious anger expression, now it's a 'mild anger'. Yes.
という感じで、あの、ちょっとね、いろんな表情ができるようになったんで、それも踏まえて、あの、ライブ見てくれると嬉しいです。
Because I can show different expressions now, I'd be happy if you keep that in mind while watching the live.
そして、ま、ノエルちゃんも変わったんですけど、この変わったね、お姿で、さらに、本日のステージはこちらです！
And while I've changed, in this new form... here is today's stage!
えー、すごいね！全景！
Wow, look at that! The full view!
わあー！なんか本当に癒やしって感じだよね！もう本当に綺麗に、はい、作っていただきました。
Whoa! It really feels healing! They made it so beautifully for me.
ま、ここのね、周り。そう、周り、これ雲、雲の海みたいな感じで、プカプカってなっています。ええ。
And all around here... yes, around us is a sea of clouds, floating softly. Yeah.
そしてね、ま、こうやって、雲の海から、上もね、すごい！綺麗！
And looking up from this sea of clouds... wow! It's so pretty!
なんか飾りがグルグルグルグルと回っておりますので、
The decorations are spinning round and round,
や、なんかね、ま、これからちょっとゲストパートとかもあるんですけど、なんかそれに合わせて色々と変わっていくみたいなので、ぜひ楽しみにしてみてください。
and it seems they'll change along with the guest segments coming up, so please look forward to that.
てな感じで、次の曲、レッツゴー！
And with that, on to the next song... Let's go!
僕は今 夢旅の中
I am now in the middle of a dream journey.
僕はいま
I am now
夢旅の中
in the middle of a dream journey.
あの星の島までも
Even to that island of a star,
飛んでゆける
I can fly there.
手のりウタうたう
Singing a song in my hand,
僕のユメクイ
my dream-eater.
君のそばにも
I can reach your side, too.
辿り着ける
I can make it there.
ユメクイ / 作詞・作曲：愛
Yumekui / Lyrics & Composition: Ai
最初描いた
I've become unable to remember
夢を思いだせなくなった
the dream I first drew.
あなたの和を
Is it because I've become
大人になったから？
an adult in your circle?
右か左かで
Whether it's right or left,
いつまでも迷ってる
I'm lost forever.
太陽が反転するまで
Until the sun reverses,
しゃべりこんだ
we talked and talked.
ひとつだけ
Only one thing
ポケットに入れてきたもの
I've kept in my pocket.
おおきな
Carrying this
この愛を持って
great love.
僕はいま
I am now
夢旅の中
in the middle of a dream journey.
あの星の島までも
Even to that island of a star,
飛んでゆける
I can fly there.
手のりウタうたう
Singing a song in my hand,
僕のユメクイ
my dream-eater.
君のそばにも
I can reach your side, too.
辿り着ける
I can make it there.
カラフルなモヤに
My heart was stolen
心を奪われ
by the colorful mist,
ちょっとしたことに
and I stumbled
つまずいた
over something small.
すりむいたところに
On the place I scraped,
君がくれたのは
what you gave me was
恥ずかしいくらいの
an almost embarrassingly
可愛らしい絆創膏
cute bandage.
叶えるたびに
Every time I make a dream come true,
食いつくすユメクイ
the dream-eater devours it.
叶えるたびに
Every time I make a dream come true,
また夢を見る
I dream again,
いくつになっても
no matter how old I get.
僕はいま
I am now
夢旅の中
in the middle of a dream journey.
寄り道して
I'll take a detour
プレゼント見つける
and find a present.
手のりウタうたう
Singing a song in my hand,
僕のユメクイ
my dream-eater.
描いた未来に
In the future I drew,
君がいつもいる
you are always there.
僕はいま
I am now
夢旅の中
in the middle of a dream journey.
あの星の島までも
Even to that island of a star,
飛んでゆける
I can fly there.
手のりウタうたう
Singing a song in my hand,
僕のユメクイ
my dream-eater.
君のそばにも
I can reach your side, too.
辿り着ける
I can make it there.
君のそばで
By your side,
ずっと夢を見る
I'll dream forever.
半端ないぱっぱらっぱっぱらっぱらっ
Incredible papparappa papparappa
（へい）
(Hey!)
限界突破らっぱっぱらっぱっぱらっぱらっ
Breaking limits papparappa papparappa
（へい）
(Hey!)
毎日半端ないぱっぱらっぱっぱらっぱらっ
Every day is incredible papparappa papparappa
（へい）
(Hey!)
限界突破らっぱっぱらっぱっぱらっぱらっ
Breaking limits papparappa papparappa
（へい）
(Hey!)
適温、うわ、幽霊が邪魔する通り道
Perfect temperature, uh, ghosts blocking my way
八百万の嫌な外部的要素
A million annoying external factors
「何の気なしと」超あっけらかんと
"Like it's nothing," completely nonchalant
悪気もなく邪魔するとかさの
Getting in the way without any ill intent
誰かが三拝々
Someone's bowing three times
自分時間 堕落タイム確保
Securing my own time, my lazy time
17時9時は死守マスト
Protecting 5 to 9 is a absolute must
さらに愛や恋や甘いも忘れずに
And don't forget about love, romance, and sweets
とどのつまり
In the end...
オーバーワークは立ち入り禁止ですよって
Overworking is strictly off-limits
注意喚起もしてますよ
I'm warning you about that too
ねえ楽して苦なくして生きてくって難しいな
Hey, living easily without suffering is hard, isn't it?
だって
Because...
安定裏技 一夜漬け
Safe tricks, last-minute cramming
甘い水には罠がある
There's a trap in the sweet water
（イヤ）
(No!)
眠くなったら寝る
If I get sleepy, I sleep
お昼過ぎに起きる
I wake up after noon
遊びたくて遊ぶ
I play because I want to play
お腹減ったらご飯を食べる
If I'm hungry, I eat a meal
嬉しかったら笑う
If I'm happy, I laugh
悲しかったら泣いてもいいんじゃない
If I'm sad, isn't it okay to cry?
明日の私のために今日もう
For the sake of the me of tomorrow, today too...
なんとか頑張るのさ
I'll somehow do my best
明日も頑張らなくていいように
So I don't have to work hard tomorrow...
頑張るのさ
I'll do my best today
損得じゃないや これ多分そうだ
It's not about profit or loss, I think so
なんやかんやでこと足りています
One way or another, it's enough
誰に知られなくたって別にいいから
It doesn't matter if no one knows
私には私のマイルール
I have my own rules
明日楽するためにはハイチーズ
Say cheese, to make tomorrow easier
意外とこんな感じでラブアンドピースのある
Unexpectedly, with this kind of love and peace...
毎日を生きたいのです
I want to live my days
ドキドキしたい
I want my heart to throb
トキメキたい
I want to feel a spark
Let me shine
明日天気になれ
Hope the weather is nice tomorrow
To be excite
To be excited
心もっと踊りたい
I want my heart to dance more
辛くなったら歌う
When it gets tough, I sing
むかついたら愚痴る
When I'm annoyed, I complain
やりたいようにやる
I'll do what I want to do
それができたら苦労しないわ
If I could do that, it wouldn't be so hard
常に一喜一憂
Always swinging between joy and sorrow
してりゃ何かしらとおもったんから
Because I thought it would lead to something
適当にセーブしつつ回避して
Saving properly while avoiding things
まぁ頑張るのさ
Well, I'll do my best
適当にとまでは言うまいが
I won't say I'll just wing it, but...
まぁ頑張るのさ
Well, I'll do my best
夢の中では
In my dreams...
ずっとぐーたらしてやるんだ
I'm going to be lazy all the time!
誰かのためとか そんなんじゃなく
It's not for someone else's sake
明日の私のために
It's for the me of tomorrow
（Fight）
(Fight!)
楽するために苦しいことも
In order to relax, even painful things...
乗り越えちゃうんだからね
I'll overcome them!
（Fight）
(Fight!)
やりたくないこと やらないために
In order not to do what I don't want to...
やりたくないこと やれ
Do the things you don't want to do!
（Fight）
(Fight!)
あれ？これって結果 頑張れてる
Wait, does this mean I'm doing my best?
私とっても偉いじゃないか
Aren't I actually very impressive?
（Fight）
(Fight!)
自分時間 堕落タイム確保
Securing my own time, my lazy time
17時9時は死守マスト
Protecting 5 to 9 is a absolute must
さらに愛や恋や甘いも忘れずに
And don't forget about love, romance, and sweets
とどのつまり
In the end...
オーバーワークは立ち入り禁止ですよって
Overworking is strictly off-limits
注意喚起もしてますよ
I'm warning you about that too
ねえ楽して苦なくして生きてくって難しいな
Hey, living easily without suffering is hard, isn't it?
だって
Because...
安定裏技 一夜漬け
Safe tricks, last-minute cramming
甘い水には罠がある
There's a trap in the sweet water
（イヤ）
(No!)
眠くなったら寝る
If I get sleepy, I sleep
お昼過ぎに起きる
I wake up after noon
遊びたくて遊ぶ
I play because I want to play
お腹減ったらご飯を食べる
If I'm hungry, I eat a meal
嬉しかったら笑う
If I'm happy, I laugh
悲しかったら泣いてもいいんじゃない
If I'm sad, isn't it okay to cry?
明日の私のために今日もう
For the sake of the me of tomorrow, today too...
なんとか頑張るのさ
I'll somehow do my best
明日も頑張らなくていいように
So I don't have to work hard tomorrow...
頑張るのさ
I'll do my best today
半端ないぱっぱらっぱっぱらっぱらっ
Incredible papparappa papparappa
（へい）
(Hey!)
限界突破らっぱっぱらっぱっぱらっぱらっ
Breaking limits papparappa papparappa
（へい）
(Hey!)
毎日半端ないぱっぱらっぱっぱらっぱらっ
Every day is incredible papparappa papparappa
（へい）
(Hey!)
限界突破らっぱっぱらっぱっぱらっぱらっ
Breaking limits papparappa papparappa
（へい）
(Hey!)
踊る暇があったら発明してえ
If I had time to dance, I'd invent something
歌う暇があったら発明してえ
If I had time to sing, I'd invent something
ライブのブッキング蹴って発明してえ
If I ditched the live booking, I'd invent something
そんな発明王にオレはなる
I will become that kind of invention king
踊る暇があったら発明してえ
If I had time to dance, I'd invent something
歌う暇があったら発明してえ
If I had time to sing, I'd invent something
ライブのブッキング蹴って発明してえ
If I ditched the live booking, I'd invent something
そんな発明王にオレはなる
I will become that kind of invention king
踊るエジソン 自尊心
Dancing Edison, self-esteem
歌うエジソン ジソン心
Singing Edison, self-esteem
踊るエジソン 自尊心
Dancing Edison, self-esteem
歌うエジソン ジソン心
Singing Edison, self-esteem
幼少期の頃から 家で聴いてた音楽はハウスミュージック
Since I was a child, the music I listened to was house
サブスクのプレイリスト聞いて 曲ディグったなら
Listening to subscription playlists, digging for songs
クラブでDJ パソコン開いたならDTM
Club DJing, opening a PC for DTM
ソフトは Ableton Live だけど今作
Software is Ableton Live, but now I'm...
だけど今作りたいのは 蓄音機
But now, what I want to make is a gramophone
サークルでの 宴会芸
Party tricks at the club
ノリで始めた バンドで
In a band we started on a whim
まぐれでバズって メジャーデビュー
We accidentally went viral and made a major debut
なぜか今はしがないミュージシャン
For some reason, now I'm just a lowly musician
踊るエジソン 自尊心
Dancing Edison, self-esteem
歌うエジソン 自尊心
Singing Edison, self-esteem
踊るエジソン 自尊心
Dancing Edison, self-esteem
歌うエジソン 自尊心
Singing Edison, self-esteem
YouTubeを見て得る1%のひらめき インスピレーション
1% inspiration from watching YouTube
SNS通して繋がる発明家のコミュニケーション
Inventors communicating through SNS
インスタ映え狙った投稿
Posts aiming for Instagrammability
webニュースで情報収集
Gathering info through web news
間違いなくこれからの時代来るのは
There's no doubt, the next big thing...
活動写真！
is motion pictures!
いや、絶対来ると思うんだけどな
No, I really think it's coming, though
踊る暇があったら発明してえ
If I have time to dance, I want to invent
歌う暇があったら発明してえ
If I have time to sing, I want to invent
ライブのブッキング 蹴って発明してえ
I'd skip my live bookings just to invent
そんな発明王にオレはなる
I'm going to be that kind of invention king
踊るエジソン 自尊心
Dancing Edison, self-esteem
歌うエジソン 自尊心
Singing Edison, self-esteem
踊るエジソン 自尊心
Dancing Edison, self-esteem
歌うエジソン 自尊心
Singing Edison, self-esteem
今日はこのまま さよならじゃないよ。
It's not goodbye like this today.
手を握ってくれたなら！
If you've taken my hand!
秘密も 眠りにつくような夜に
On a night where even secrets fall asleep,
君を連れていくよ
I'll take you away
それは例えば 遠く離れていたって
Even if, for example, we were far apart,
手を繋いでいられるような
so that we can still hold hands...
奇跡のような 話をしよう
Let's talk about something like a miracle
窓は開けておいて
Keep the window open
今日までを思いだして
Remembering everything up until today,
一つずつ並べたら
if I lined them up one by one,
明日の雨が気になりだして
I'd start worrying about tomorrow's rain
どうも眠れないみたいだ
I guess I just can't sleep
変わりたくないことや
Things I don't want to change,
変わらなきゃいけないことも
and things that have to change...
少し忘れたまま
While forgetting them for a bit,
窓の外を眺めていたんだ
I was looking out the window
雨が降り出すその前に
Before the rain starts to fall,
君のところまで 行けるような気がして
I feel like I can make it to where you are,
目を閉じてみたんだ
so I tried closing my eyes
そしてこのまま 遠くへと行こう！
And let's go far away just like this!
手を取ってくれるかな。
I wonder if you'll take my hand.
秘密も 眠りにつくような夜を
A night where even secrets fall asleep,
君と泳いでいくよ
I'll swim through it with you
街の明かりが 消えるたびに笑って
Smiling every time the city lights go out,
路地裏で抱き合おう
let's embrace in the back alley
馬鹿みたいな 話をしよう
Let's talk about something silly
窓は開けておいて
Keep the window open
聞こえる？
Can you hear it?
愛おしいことや
Precious things and
無くせないものを
things that can't be lost,
教えてくれたのは 今日みたいな
what taught me was a night like today...
夜を重ねて 織り上げてきた
Layering nights together to weave
私たちに響く音
the sound that resonates within us
夜が来るたびに 心が踊ってしまうのは
Every time night comes, my heart starts to dance because...
また一つ重なっていく
they're layering together once again
目を閉じてみたんだ
I tried closing my eyes.
今夜
Tonight,
私たちだけで眠ろう
let's sleep with just us.
誰にも言わないで
Don't tell anyone.
君が眠りにつくその少し前に
Just a little before you fall asleep...
名前を呼んで
call my name.
叶わない願いに胸は痛んで
My heart aches with unfulfilled wishes,
うつむいてしまうけど
and I look down, but...
誰もいない街へ誘いに行くから
I'm going to invite you to a town where no one is around.
今日はこのままさよならじゃないよ
It's not a goodbye like this today.
手をとってくれたなら
If you would take my hand,
秘密も眠りにつくような夜に
to a night where even secrets fall asleep,
君を連れていくよ
I will take you away.
それは例えば、遠く離れていたって
That is, for example, even if we were far apart,
手を繋いでいられるような
like we could keep holding hands,
奇跡のような話をしよう
let's talk about a miracle-like story.
窓は開けておいて
Keep the window open.
聞こえる？
Can you hear it?
愛おしいことや、無くせないものを
The things I cherish and the things I cannot lose...
教えてくれたのは今日みたいな夜
it was a night like today that taught me.
夜を重ねて
Layering the nights,
織り上げてきた私たちに響く音
the sound that resonates within us, who have woven them together.
はい！ということで皆さん、今回のライブ、なんと
Yes! So everyone, in this live, I have...
新衣装がポポポポポポーン！ありましたー！
a new outfit! Ta-da!
ということで、あのびっくりしたかな？
So, were you surprised?
びっくりしたんじゃないかなと思います。
I think you probably were.
あのこちらね、すごい、きらびやかな衣装と
This is a very gorgeous outfit,
なっているんですけど、スクショタイム取る？
but should we take a screenshot time now?
えーい。可愛いいですか？
Yay. Am I cute?
ぜひ、ハッシュタグで呟いてください。
Please, tweet using the hashtag.
可愛いでしょ。
I'm cute, right?
何やらね、この後ちょっと衣装のね、色々、
I have a feeling I'll have a chance to look
細部まで見る機会がありそうな予感…
at the details of the outfit later...
そして、あとこちらね、見て。手首に
And look at this. There are these
プラプラーって紐があるんだけど、取れます。
strings on my wrists, but they come off.
じゃ、取ってもらおうかな？はい！はい！
Should I have them taken off? There! There!
ということで、はい、取れます。そう。
So, yes, they come off.
こちらバージョンもスクショ撮ってもらおう。
Let's take screenshots of this version too.
えーい。可愛いですか？ぴゃー。
Yay. Am I cute? Pyaa.
ね、すごい可愛らしい衣装。
It's such a lovely outfit.
ちょっとね、ドキドキするんですが、うーん。
I'm a little nervous, though...
いやーなんか、でもちょっと一人寂しいな。
Man, it's a bit lonely by myself.
なんかだれか、うーん。
I wish someone...
あ！ありゃ可愛いね。お、なんかむぞむぞしてる。
Ah! That's cute. Oh, something's wiggling.
お、どうしたどうしたどうした。
What's wrong?
うわー！だんいんさん飛んできたー！
Whoa! A Dan-in flew in!
そんなにノエルちゃんに会いたかったんかな。
Did you want to see Noel-chan that much?
可愛いねー。いっぱいスクショ撮れた？
So cute. Did you get lots of screenshots?
んー。だんいんさんとのツーショット。
Mmm. A two-shot with a Dan-in.
可愛いええな。あ、今日は安眠テーマで、
It's cute. Ah, today's theme is sleep,
心地がいい。あ、なるほどね。
so it's comfortable. I see.
ん？曲のリクエスト。あ、子守唄みたいな
Hmm? A song request. Oh, you want to
曲が聴きたい。あ、そうなんだ、だんいんさん。
hear a lullaby. I see, Mr. Dan-in.
じゃせっかくだんいんさん来てくれたし、
Well, since you're here,
一緒に、じゃ子守唄、うん。歌うよ、歌う。
let's sing a lullaby together. I'll sing.
だからちょっとついてきて。一緒に行くよ。
So follow me for a bit. Let's go together.
小さな人の子よ
Oh, little child of man,
森へ迷い込んだ
wandered into the forest.
大きな足音に怯えなくていいよ
Don't be afraid of the loud footsteps.
大きなこの羽根が
These large wings,
ぼうやは見えないのね
You can't see them, can you?
なにも知らない
Knowing nothing,
まあるいほっぺよ
With your round cheeks,
眠れや 眠れ
Sleep, oh sleep!
静かな水辺においで
Come to the quiet waterside.
ぼうやの夢は
A little boy's dream
龍の背に運ばれて
Is carried on the back of a dragon,
山の向こうへ消える
And vanishes beyond the mountains.
よろずの子らも
All the children, too,
並んで眠る
Sleep in a row.
七つ数えたら
When you count to seven,
仲良く眠ってく
Sleep peacefully together.
なにも見えない
With your little eyes
小さなお目目よ
That see nothing,
眠れや 眠れ
Sleep, oh sleep!
そよぐ草むらへおいで
Come to the rustling grasses.
ぼうやの夢は
A little boy's dream
母さんを探しては
Goes searching for its mother,
空の向こうへ帰る
And returns beyond the sky.
龍の背に運ばれて
Carried on the back of a dragon,
山の向こうへ消える
It vanishes beyond the mountains.
プラネタリウム
Planetarium
夕月夜 顔だす 消えてく
The evening moon appears, then disappears
子供の声と
Along with the voices of children
遠く 遠く
Far, far away
この空のどこかに君はいるんだろ
Somewhere in this sky, you must be there
夏の終わりに2人で
At the end of summer, the two of us
抜け出した この公園で見つけた
Slipped away and found in this park
あの星座 何だか覚えてる
Do you remember what that constellation was?
会えなくても 記憶をたどって
Even if we can't meet, I'll trace my memories
同じ幸せを見たいんだ
I want to see the same happiness
あの香りと共に 花火がパッと開く
Along with that scent, fireworks suddenly bloom
行きたいよ 君のところへ
I want to go to where you are
今すぐ かけだして 行きたいよ
I want to run and go to you right now
まっ暗で なにも見えない 怖くても
It's pitch black and I can't see anything, but even if I'm scared...
大丈夫
It's okay
数えきれない 星空が
A countless starry sky
今もずっと ここにあるんだよ
Is still right here, even now
泣かないよ
I won't cry
君と見た きれいな空だったから
Because it was the beautiful sky I saw with you
あの道まで
Until that road...
響く靴の音が耳に残る
the sound of echoing shoes remains in my ears
大きな自分の
My large...
影を見つめて想うのでしょう
shadow is what I gaze at and think of, I suppose
ちっとも変わらないはずなのに
Even though nothing should have changed at all
せつない気持ちふくらんでく
These sad feelings keep swelling up
どんなに想ったって
No matter how much I think of you,
君はもういない
you're not here anymore
行きたいよ
I want to go
君のそばに
to your side
ちいさくても
Even if it's small,
even if it's small,
一番に
More than anyone,
君が好きだよ
I love you
つよくいられる
I can stay strong
願いを
A wish...
流れ星に
to a shooting star
そっと唱えてみたけれど
I tried whispering quietly, but...
泣きたいよ
I want to cry
届くだろう
It should reach you,
きれいな空に
to the beautiful sky
会えなくても 記憶をたどって
Even if we can't meet, I trace my memories
同じ幸せを見たいんだ
I want to see the same happiness
あの香りと共に 花火がぱっと開く
Along with that scent, fireworks burst open
行きたいよ
I want to go
君のところへ
to where you are
小さな手を握りしめて
Holding your small hand tightly
泣きたいよ
I want to cry
それはそれは きれいな空だった
It was such a beautiful sky
願いを
A wish...
流れ星に
to a shooting star
そっと唱えてみたけれど
I tried whispering quietly, but...
泣きたいよ
I want to cry
届かない想いを この空に...
These feelings that won't reach you, to this sky...
もう何十回
Dozens of times already,
もう何百回も
hundreds of times already,
霞むソラ見上げて
I've looked up at the hazy sky
辿り着いた場所が
The place I reached is
運命のダイヤモンド
the diamond of destiny
何千回
Thousands of times,
もう何万回も
tens of thousands of times already,
涙流したきみへ
to you who shed tears
ねぇ
Hey,
諦められたことはあったっけ？
have you ever given up?
「憧れ＝限界」だから もういらないよ
Since "Longing = Limit," I don't need it anymore
そこに留まるなんてもったいないでしょ？
It's a waste to just stay there, right?
それぞれの物語
Our respective stories,
交差する瞬間を
at the moment they cross
見つめる意味は
The meaning of staring is...
放った夢だけ
Only the dream I released,
大きな弧を描いて
drawing a big arc
はちきれそうな
The about-to-burst
煌めきを
sparkling
消えることなく
without disappearing
どこまでもでも
wherever it may be
世界の向こうに
Beyond the world
届けよう
Let's deliver it
終わることのない
Never-ending...
この胸の衝動は
...this impulse in my heart
どうしたって どうしても
No matter what, no matter how
ぼくを呼んでいた
It was calling out to me
だから
And so...
その先へと
...towards what lies beyond
走り続ける
I will keep on running
次へ 次へ
To the next, to the next
妄想だって
Even if it's a delusion
中途半端な
This half-hearted...
ふがいないさ抱えて
...worthlessness I carry
立ち尽くしていた
Had me standing still
通り雨は
The passing rain...
プレリュード
...is a prelude
何千回 もう何万回も
Thousands, tens of thousands of times
挑み続けた君へ
To you who kept on challenging
ねぇ 聴かせてよ
Hey, let me hear it
「夢は叶うんだ」って
Say that "dreams do come true"
「諦め＝完敗」ならば
If "giving up = complete defeat"
絶対にないよ
That'll never happen
だれに邪魔されようと
No matter who tries to stop me
ためらわないで
Don't hesitate
託された情熱を
The passion entrusted to us
落とさずにつないでいく
We'll pass it on without dropping it
そう最後まで
Yes, until the very end
フラッグに誓い
Vow on the flag
雄々しくはためいて
Fluttering bravely
鳴り止まないファンファーレ
The never-ending fanfare
いつも心に
It was always...
流れていた
...flowing in my heart
遠い未来へ
To the distant future
祈るように
Like a prayer
忘れられない
Unforgettable...
あの日々の後悔を
...the regrets of those days
追いかけて
Chasing them...
...chasing them
滑り込んだ
Slipped into...
この想い
...this feeling
青い空に
Into the blue sky
ふと溢れていった
Suddenly it overflowed
遠く遠く
Far, far away
終わらない 終わらない
Not ending, not ending
仕事が山積み終わらない
Work is piling up and it's not ending
止まらない 止まらない
Not stopping, not stopping
それでも時間は止まらない
But even so, time doesn't stop
YO YO!
ヘトヘト たまりたまったヘトヘト
Exhausted, piled up exhaustion
天罰！ お返しバット！
Heavenly punishment! Return bat!
コンボ 命ず 金属バット
Order a combo, metal bat!
Swing!
今日も目一杯 今日も目一杯
To the fullest today too, to the fullest today too
Round!
NO MORE 鞭
No more whip
GIVE ME GIVE ME 汁
Give me, give me juicy
I see!
微笑 Anytime 微笑 Anytime
Smiling anytime, smiling anytime
はぁー
[Sigh]
溜めてたブレスで MP空っぽ
With a stored breath, MP is empty
参上!
Appearing!
自分自身に厳しすぎちゃう
Being too hard on myself
すぐさまヘラヘラ優等生
Immediately a grinning honor student
さっぱり足りない 向上性
Not enough upward mobility at all
自分自身としっかり向き合う
Facing myself properly
1番必要（なものは）
What's needed most...
トレビアン
...is Très Bien!
ご褒美頂戴
Give me a reward
Wah!
てんてこ舞うよなリズムに
To a frantic rhythm...
バイバイしちゃえ
...say bye-bye to it
ドレミファのお供にご覧
Look, as a companion to Do-Re-Mi-Fa
Wah!
きゅきゅっと詰め込んじゃえ
Stuff it in tightly
どんどんフリーダム
More and more freedom
Uh!
オーライ オーライ
All right, all right
好きなもの食べ放題
All-you-can-eat of my favorite things
オキシトシン増します脳内
Oxytocin increases in my brain
ほらもっともっと頂戴
Look, give me more and more
膨大
Enormous!
Get ready!
多忙です たまに空振り
I'm busy, occasionally swinging and missing
満ち足りた日こそ 胸張り大盛り
On days I'm satisfied, chest out, extra large serving
いらない まやかしの甘い夜菓子
Don't need deceptive sweet night snacks
ハッピーになるため歌おう
Let's sing to be happy
声高らかに
With our voices raised high
Yeah!
自分自身がやっぱり一番
Myself is after all number one
理性と欲望が平行線
Reason and desire are parallel lines
望みは幸せエンドレス
Wishing for endless happiness
自分自身としっかり向き合う
Facing myself properly
我慢は体に
Restraint is... for the body...
毒だよ
...poison
トレビアン
Très Bien!
ご褒美頂戴
Give me a reward
Wah!
てんてこ舞うよなリズムに
To a frantic rhythm...
バイバイしちゃえ
...say bye-bye to it
ドレミファのお供にご覧
Look, as a companion to Do-Re-Mi-Fa
Wah!
きゅきゅっと詰め込んじゃえ
Stuff it in tightly
どんどんフリーダム
More and more freedom
1, 2, の, 3, はい!
1, 2, 3, go!
窮屈な靴に疲弊ストレス
Exhaustion and stress from tight shoes
状態異常から解放すべ
A way to release from abnormal status
もっともっと
More and more,
more and more!
まだまだ足りない
It's still not enough!
本日は欲望
Today is a desire-
解放パーティーナイト
-releasing party night!
乾杯！
Cheers!
トレビアン 極上を
Très bien, give me
ちょうだい
the finest!
てんてこ舞いなリズムに
To the hectic rhythm,
バイバイしちゃえ
let's say goodbye!
トレビアン 踊りに
Très bien, come
ご来
to dance!
ぎゅうぎゅうと詰めちゃだめ
Don't pack it in tight,
どんどんフリーダム
more and more freedom!
ぎゅうぎゅうと夢のご褒美
Squeeze in the reward of dreams,
どんどん好きになる
and I'll love it more and more!
フィーバー！
Fever!
おいで！ おいで！
Come on! Come on!
誘惑の Dance again
Tempting dance again!
おいでよおいで！
Come on, come on!
輝夜の城へ
To Kaguya's castle!
出逢いがあやつるミステリー
A mystery manipulated by an encounter,
危険なペルソナ
a dangerous persona.
踊ろう！ 踊ろう！
Let's dance! Let's dance!
終わらない Dance beat
An unending dance beat!
踊ろうよ踊ろう！
Let's dance, let's dance!
輝夜の城で
At Kaguya's castle!
夜空を切りとるレーザービーム
A laser beam cutting through the night sky...
私と見てよ？
Will you watch it with me?
まばゆい星が照らす想い
Feelings illuminated by dazzling stars,
今宵の夢よ永遠に
may this evening's dream be eternal.
明日のことは忘れたいの
I want to forget about tomorrow...
ニパッ
Nipa!
私は紅い 薔薇の姫よ
I am the crimson princess of roses.
激しくさらわれたい
I want to be intensely carried away...
そっと囁いて
Whisper softly.
意味ありげに目をそらす
Looking away with a meaningful look,
あなたは白月の騎士
you are the knight of the white moon.
触れた手がまだ熱い
The hand that touched me is still hot,
のがさずに抱きしめて
hold me without letting go.
この奇跡を恋と呼ぶのね
You call this miracle love, right?
おいで！ おいで！
Come on! Come on!
情熱の Dance again
Passionate dance again!
おいでよおいで！
Come on, come on!
輝夜の城へ
To Kaguya's castle!
迷いを飲みこむエナジー
Energy that swallows up hesitation,
眠らぬパッショネイト
sleepless passionate.
踊ろう！ 踊ろう！
Let's dance! Let's dance!
止まらない Dance beat
An unstoppable dance beat!
踊ろうよ踊ろう！
Let's dance, let's dance!
輝夜の城で
At Kaguya's castle!
星座が織りなすディスコティーク
A discotheque woven by the constellations...
私も混ぜて？
Can I join too?
きらめく星に誓う心
A heart swearing to the sparkling stars,
儚い夢でいいわ
a fleeting dream is fine.
明日は明日の風が吹くの
Tomorrow's wind will blow tomorrow...
だよねー！
Right?!
私は黒い 薔薇の姫よ
I am the black princess of roses.
激しくさらわれたい
I want to be intensely carried away,
だから微笑んで
so please smile.
追いかけて目が誘う
Chasing after you, my eyes invite you,
あなたも黒い月の騎士
you too are the knight of the black moon.
瞳の奥は熱い
Deep in your eyes, it's hot,
つかまえて抱きしめて
catch me and hold me.
この奇跡は恋を呼ぶのね
This miracle calls for love, right?
一緒に行こう？
Let's go together?
ついてきて？
Follow me?
他の人を見ちゃイヤ！
Don't look at anyone else!
私だけを見て♥
Look only at me♥
後悔するわよ？
You'll regret it, you know?
楽しもう！
Let's have fun!
早くしなさいよ！
Hurry up already!
鈍いのですね...
You're quite slow...
いいの？
Is it okay?
私は紅い 薔薇の姫よ
I am the crimson princess of roses.
激しくさらわれたい
I want to be intensely carried away...
そっと囁いて
Whisper softly.
意味ありげに目をそらす
Looking away with a meaningful look,
あなたは白い月の騎士
you are the knight of the white moon.
触れた手がまだ熱い
The hand that touched me is still hot,
のがさずに抱きしめて
hold me without letting go.
この奇跡を恋と呼ぶのね
You call this miracle love, right?
はい！
Yes!
ということで、3期生の皆と
So, with everyone from the 3rd generation,
『輝夜の城で踊りたい』を歌って踊りました！
we sang and danced to "Kaguya no Shiro de Odoritai"!
イエーイ！
Yeah!
ノエちゃん、お誕生日おめでとう！
No-chan, happy birthday!
ありがとう～！
Thank you~!
ちょっと可愛いんじゃない？
Isn't she kind of cute?
え、可愛い？
Eh, am I cute?
ちょっと服装に対して動きが…
Your movements for that outfit are...
動きがちょっと…
your movements are a bit...
ちょっとね、あの、素敵に…
Well, you know, beautifully...
可愛いですか？
Am I cute?
可愛い！
You're cute!
凄いね、なんかここがね…
It's amazing, like, this part right here...
ね、重い、ここ大丈夫ですか？
Yeah, it's heavy, is this part okay?
おっぱいがお尻だよ、ノエちゃん。
Your breasts are like butts, No-chan.
こんなのおっぱいに挨拶しちゃう。
I'm going to greet breasts like these.
いや、でも今日からはさ、こう話せばいいのか？
No, but from today on, should I talk like this?
そんなわけないだろ！
As if that would happen!
今回のね衣装はね、あの、200万人の記念で、
This outfit was made to commemorate
はい、作っていただきました。
reaching 2 million subscribers.
おお！
Oh!
他にも変わったところ、今日のライブからであるんだけど…
There are other changes from today's live, though...
ノエちゃん、気づいた？
No-chan, did you notice?
へ？メイク…？
Eh? Makeup...?
ああ！気づいた！
Ah! You noticed!
そうなんですよ。ちょっとメイク変わりました。え、大丈夫？
That's right. My makeup changed a bit. Is it okay?
全然違う！可愛い！
It's completely different! So cute!
ちなみにお気に入りの顔がありましてね…
By the way, I have a favorite expression...
お困り顔、お困り顔がね。
the troubled face, the troubled face.
そう、可愛いでしょ？お口がね、ちょっとクリになってるんです。
Isn't it cute? My mouth is shaped like a chestnut.
ああ、本当だ！クリになってる！
Ah, it's true! It's shaped like a chestnut!
こだわりの…食べちゃおう…
The attention to detail... let's eat it...
うわあ！
Whoa!
うわあじゃなかった。え、じゃあちょっと衣装、せっかくなんで…
It wasn't 'whoa'. Well, since we're here, let's look at the outfit...
そうだね。下からちょっと舐めるように…
Right. Let's scan it starting from the bottom...
いきましょうよ。靴から見ましょう、靴から。
Let's do it. Let's look at the shoes first.
おろ、可愛い！お靴！
Oh, they're cute! The shoes!
いいでしょ？よく見せて。あ、ヒールなのです。
Good, right? Look closely. Ah, they have heels.
可愛いです！
They're cute!
リボンついてる！普段はね、通常でぺったんこだから、
They have ribbons! Usually, I wear flats,
ちょっと身長盛りました。
so I added some height.
リボン二個構え、後ろにね！
There are two ribbons on the back!
そうなんですよ。え、可愛い！
That's right. Wow, cute!
いいね、いいね！じゃあちょっと舐めるように…
Nice, nice! Now, let's scan upwards...
ううう！
Ooooh!
一体どんなおぱんつ…
What kind of panties are you wearing...
あ、これ！
Ah, this!
なに変態モード？好奇心が…
What's with the pervert mode? Your curiosity is...
え、こんな感じで…え、ちょっとそんなサササと終わんないよ。
Well, like this... hey, don't finish it so quickly.
まだ舐めてる最中。
We're still in the middle of scanning.
あああ！ノエルちゃん！
Aaaa! Noel-chan!
ここね！ノエルちゃんじゃなくて、ノエルちゃん！
Here! It's not Noel-chan, it's Noel-chan!
皆さんご覧ください、ここなのこのこのこのこの胸の…
Everyone, please look, this this this this chest part...
ここなの…この隙間隙間隙間！
right here... this gap, gap, gap!
分かります？このちちとちちの間の隙間。
Do you see it? This gap between my breasts.
本当だ、凄いね！
It's true, it's amazing!
この穴…隙間がね、ほら！
This hole... the gap, look!
うわあ！
Whoa!
大丈夫でこか？大丈夫でこか？
Is it okay to look? Is it okay to look?
最高の衣装！
The best outfit ever!
じゃあちょっと上見せるにあたって、このヒラヒラ取れるから、
To show the top part better, these frills can be removed,
ちょっと…ちょっと取ってもいい？
so... can I take them off?
あ、取ってみて、取ってみて！はい！取ってください！
Ah, try it, try it! Yes! Please take them off!
おお！見やすい！
Oh! It's much easier to see!
そう、見やすい。バンザイ！
Yes, easy to see. Banzai!
え、横はどうなっているのか？
Eh, what does it look like from the side?
ゆっくりくるくる回って。
Turn around slowly.
くるくるくる…
Spin, spin, spin...
あ、髪の毛可愛い！髪の毛ふわふわで可愛い！
Ah, the hair is cute! It's so fluffy and cute!
ふわふわだよ！髪型めちゃ可愛い！え、お姫様！
It's fluffy! The hairstyle is super cute! Like a princess!
え、なんかリボンがこう髪にね、こう巻き込んである感じで。
It's like the ribbons are wrapped into the hair.
そうなんね。編み込んで。え、エッチも言ってましたけど、
That's right. They're braided in. I mentioned being an "Ecchi-mo",
姫騎士なんで、お姫様。
but since I'm a Princess Knight, I'm a princess.
可愛すぎる！こんなの好きになっちゃう。
Too cute! I'm going to end up falling for this.
ちょっと彼氏面したいからちょっといつもの動きして。
I want to act like a boyfriend, so do your usual move.
待ってた、待ってた！あはは！なんか好きじゃなくなった。
I've been waiting for that! Ahaha! I don't like it anymore.
なんでよ！
Why?!
危ない、危ない。恋するところだった。
That was close. I almost fell in love.
いや、でも本当に可愛い衣装、本当にありがとう。
But really, it's a lovely outfit. Thank you so much.
新衣装お披露目だったから、皆にはちょっと
Since it was my new outfit debut,
アイドル衣装だったんですけど。
everyone else was in their idol outfits.
そう、え、皆もさ、衣装持ってるじゃん。
Right, but everyone else has their own outfits too.
お、そうよね。並んだりとかも今後したいな。
Oh, that's right. I'd love to stand in line with you all later.
絶対しよう！また歌って踊りたいな！
Let's definitely do it! I want to sing and dance together again!
え、ちょっとそれ、お楽しみに！あったかな？
Wait, look forward to that! Was there such a plan?
はい！ということで、ここから大事なお知らせをたくさんしていきます！
Yes! So, I have many important announcements to make from here!
お願いします！
Please go ahead!
ホロライブ3期生の単独ライブ、『ききみるるん大作戦』開催決定しております！
The hololive 3rd generation's solo live, "Kirurun Daisakusen", has been confirmed!
イエイ！おめでとう！
Yay! Congratulations!
2026年1月の17日と18日の二日間にわたって開催されます！
It will be held over two days, January 17th and 18th, 2026!
いや、会場はね、あのデッカイ、Kアリーナ横浜となってます。
And the venue is that huge one, K-Arena Yokohama.
昨日ね、なんと、まちょっと二次先行…ちょうどね、終わったことなんだけど。
Yesterday, the second lottery... it just ended, actually.
なんかね、このあと、ま先着の一般販売が12月の14日…
Somehow, after this, general sales start on December 14th...
ぜひぜひ あの
Please,
勝ち取ってください
go and grab them!
お願いします！
Please do!
そして配信チケットはね
And about the streaming tickets,
まだありますので
they're still available.
はい 絶賛発売中ですので
Yes, they're currently on sale,
よろしくお願いいたします
so please check them out.
お願いします！
We're counting on you!
そして まぁこのライブを見てくださった方で
And, well, for those who watched this live,
まぁ買い忘れてる人はいないと思うけど
I don't think anyone forgot to buy them, but...
あのグッズのね 先行販売と
The advance sales and
受注販売も
made-to-order sales for the merchandise
明日のね えー11月25日の18時までとなっております
are available until 6 PM tomorrow, Nov 25th.
明日ね
Tomorrow, right?
そう だから あのライブ会場でペンライト振りたいとか
Right. So, if you want to wave a penlight at the venue,
配信見ながらペンライト振りたいよって人はぜひ
or while watching the stream,
この機会をお見逃しなく！
please don't miss this chance!
現地行く人は是非とも絶対絶対
If you're going to the venue, you'll definitely
あった方が盛り上がりますよ
have much more fun with one!
お願いします！
Please check it out!
いや 楽しみだね
Man, I'm so excited.
めっちゃ楽しみ！
We're so excited!
そう 演目もね ちょっとお目色を変えたから
Yeah, I even changed the program a bit.
おお そうなんだ！ 全部楽しみ！
Oh, really?! We're excited for everything!
そんな感じで せっかくね来てくれたから
Anyway, since you're all here,
意気込みを一言ちょっと
how about a quick word of enthusiasm?
一言ね 言おうかな
A word, huh? Let's do it.
爆するぞ！
Let's blow it up!
誰からいく？
Who's going first?
爆する！
Let's blow it up!
あ ちょっと待って
Ah, wait a second.
やる気満々だぞ
I'm raring to go!
じゃあ ちょっとマリンからこういう順番で
Okay, let's go in this order starting with Marine.
オッケー オッケー
Okay, okay!
マリンすごい良いこと言ってくれるんだろうな
Marine is going to say something great, I bet.
頑張るぞー！
I'll do my best!
おーい！
Hey!
楽しむぞー！
I'll have a blast!
おー 一言ね
Oh, just one word?
みんなで盛り上げるぞー！
Let's all get excited together!
おー ありがとう！
Oh, thank you!
え え 何？ あ あれ？
Eh, what? Oh, wait?
光の速さで去っていった
They left at the speed of light.
みんなありがとう！
Thanks, everyone!
てな感じで えーここからは
And with that, from here on,
ノエルちゃんの告知に行きます！
it's time for Noel-chan's announcements!
えー まず1つ目はこちら！
First up is this!
白銀ノエル 誕生記念 2025
Shirogane Noel Birthday Celebration 2025
はい 今年も出ます
Yes, it's out again this year!
白銀ノエル 誕生記念 2025のグッズ！
Shirogane Noel Birthday Celebration 2025 merch!
わーい！
Yay!
生誕グッズ まずはこちら！
First birthday item is this!
睡夢の世界へ！ キラキラLEDアートパネル
To the World of Suimu! Sparkling LED Art Panel
えー イラストはMyungYi先生が
This was illustrated by
描いてくれました ありがとうございます
MyungYi-sensei. Thank you so much!
いつもお世話になってます ラブチラブチラ
Thanks for your support as always! Love you!
今回のね 生誕ライブのステージと
The theme is the stage of this birthday live
新衣装がテーマになっております
and my new outfit.
まぁLEDということで こちら
Since it has LEDs,
光る ということでね
it actually glows!
ぜひお部屋に飾って
Please display it in your room
あの今回のライブを思い出して
and let it remind you of this live.
そう 思い出にしてください
Yes, keep it as a memory.
はい そして次はこちら！
Okay, next is this!
色んなノエルちゃん♡ランダムマルチバンド
Various Noel-chan Random Multi-Bands
ということで まえり先生が
These were illustrated by
描いてくれました ありがとうございます
Maeri-sensei. Thank you so much!
いや 色んなね ノエルちゃんがいますので
There are many different Noel-chans,
まぁちょっと どのノエルちゃんがね
so look forward to seeing
おうちに来るかなってちょっと楽しみにしつつ
which one comes to your house.
届いたらね マルチバンドこちら
Once they arrive, these multi-bands
あの お片付けの必需品となってます
are a must-have for tidying up!
ノエルちゃんも使っておりますので
Noel-chan uses them too,
あの ぜひねコードまとめる時とか
so they're great for organizing your cables.
はい 実用性に富んでますので
Yes, they're very practical,
使ってみてください
so please give them a try!
次は えーこちら！
Next is... this!
姫騎士ノエル ぬいぐるみキーホルダー
Princess Knight Noel Plushie Keychain
ということで 昨年はね
Last year,
あの サンタさんのノエルちゃんが
Noel-chan as Santa was
ぬいぐるみとして はい キーホルダー出たんですが
released as a plushie keychain, but...
今回は せっかく新衣装が出たので
Since we got a new outfit this time,
えー こちらでぬいぐるみキーホルダーを
we made a plushie keychain
えー 作りました
featuring it!
あの 姫騎士として団員さんを守りますので
I'll protect the order members as a knight,
ぜひ肌身離さず えー持っててください
so please keep it with you always.
えー 次は こちら！
Next is... this!
わんちょむ2wayネックピロー
Wanchomu 2-way Neck Pillow
ということで 安眠にね最適な
This neck pillow is perfect for
ネックピローなんですけど 今回は
a good night's sleep, but this time...
なんと ひっくり返すとわんちょむになっている
if you flip it inside out, it's Wanchomu!
ということで わんちょむはね
Wanchomu is the dog
あの 今年から団長のおうちに
I welcomed into my home this year,
お迎えしたわんちゃんのことなんですけど
and I turned him into merchandise!
グッズにしちゃいました
It's a passion project!
えー ちょっとね あのノエルちゃんの愛
A bit of Noel-chan's personal feelings
あの 私情が入ってますということで
are in this one.
ぜひ団員さんのおうちにもお迎えしてください
Please welcome him into your home too!
最後にフルセットを見てみましょう
Finally, let's look at the full set.
こちら！
Here it is!
はい 今年もいっぱいいっぱい
Yes, lots and lots of merch
グッズが出ました
came out this year too!
いや ぜひぜひ
Definitely
あの ゲットしてみてね
try to get one.
そして このね全部の
And for this entire full set,
フルセット特典があります
there are special bonuses.
それはこちら！
Those are these!
はい ということでフルセットを購入してくださった方に
For those who purchase the full set,
チェキ風ブロマイドカード ついてきます！
a cheki-style bromide card is included!
えー とっても素敵
It's really lovely.
まぁ イラストはね MyungYi先生のイラストで
It uses MyungYi-sensei's illustration.
こちらに えっと
And on this...
あの 通常バージョンは箔押しの
The regular version has a
複製サインが
foil-stamped signature,
あの ペタってなるんですけど
but...
えー 数量限定バージョンは
the limited-quantity version comes with
団長の直筆サインがついてきます！
Danchou's handwritten signature!
あの 心を込めて書きますので
I'll write them with all my heart,
ぜひゲットしてみてください
so please try to get it.
さらにね さらにさらに フルセットを
And furthermore, for everyone who
購入してくれた方全員に
buys the full set,
特典ボイスもついてきちゃいます！
a special bonus voice is included!
ぜひゲットしてみてください
Please be sure to get it!
ボイスも！
The voice too!
生誕グッズは心を込めて撮りました！
I put my heart into these birthday goods photos!
生誕グッズは22時カートオープンです！
The birthday goods shop opens at 10 PM!
皆さんぜひゲットしてください！
Everyone, please go and get them!
さらにさらに、重大告知があります！
And wait, there's another major announcement!
新曲があります！
I have a new song!
スペシャルな方からコメントを頂いてるみたい！
I've received a comment from someone special!
え、誰なんだろう？誰でしょうか？
Wait, who is it? I wonder who it could be?
こんまっする〜！
Konmassuru!
白銀ノエルさん、お誕生日おめでとうございます！
Shirogane Noel-san, happy birthday!
そして配信の皆さん、楽しんでいらっしゃいますか？
And to everyone watching, are you enjoying the stream?
大分県知事の佐藤樹一郎です。
I am Kiichiro Sato, the Governor of Oita Prefecture.
大分県宣伝部長、めじろんです！
And Oita's PR Manager, Mejiron!
この度は新曲の発表もおめでとうございます。
Congratulations on the announcement of your new song.
今回、私が新曲のタイトル発表を任せて頂くことになりました。
I've been honored with announcing the song title.
それでは早速、曲名を発表したいと思います。
Now, I'd like to announce the title immediately.
その名も…
The title is...
VAVAVA！バーチャル大分
VAVAVA! Virtual Oita
バーチャル大分わーい！
Virtual Oita, yay!
大分をバーチャルで楽しめるような歌なのかな。
I suppose it's a song to enjoy Oita virtually.
大分のオススメ、まずは何と言っても温泉です！
Speaking of Oita, first and foremost is hot springs!
大分県は源泉数、湧出量ともに全国一位ですから。
Oita ranks first in Japan for both sources and output.
他にも関アジ、関サバ、かぼすブリ…
There's also Seki Aji, Seki Saba, Kabosu Yellowtail...
大分和牛、唐揚げなど食の魅力も満載ですね。
Oita Wagyu and fried chicken—the food is amazing too.
ぜひ、皆さんにも味わっていただきたいです！
I really want everyone to experience it!
これからも大分県のPRを頼むけん、ノエルさん！
Keep promoting Oita Prefecture for us, Noel-san!
それでは、おつまーする〜！
Well then, Otsumassuru!
おつまーする！まさかの大分県知事さん！
Otsumassuru! I can't believe it was the Governor!
応援のコメントを頂きました！ありがとうございます！
I received a support comment! Thank you so much!
本当にびっくりで、サプライズなんですけれど。
I'm genuinely shocked; it was a total surprise.
ずっと団長大分育ちで、大分の魅力を伝えてきました。
I grew up in Oita, so I've always shared its charms.
ということで、新曲歌っちゃいたいと思います。
So, I'm going to perform my new song.
聴いてください、VAVAVA！バーチャル大分。
Please listen: VAVAVA! Virtual Oita.
説明しよう バーチャル大分とは、
Let me explain: what is Virtual Oita?
バーチャル九州の北東部に位置する広大な大地
It is a vast land in the northeast of Virtual Kyushu
現実の大分県に限りなく近い地上の楽園。
A paradise on earth, incredibly close to the real Oita.
人はその地を、バーチャル大分と呼ぶ！
People call that land, Virtual Oita!
ババババ！バーチャル大分 世に放つ
VAVAVA! Virtual Oita, unleash it to the world
ババババ！バーチャル大分 湯を沸かす
VAVAVA! Virtual Oita, boil the hot spring water
君とバーチャル大分 駆け巡る
Running around with you in Virtual Oita
ババババ！バーチャル大分 大分どーん！
VAVAVA! Virtual Oita, Oita! Boom!
君は降り立つ 魅惑の地獄の入り口
You step into the entrance of the alluring Hells
絶えず湯涌く 誘惑の地
A land of temptation where hot water always flows
海 かまど 白池 血の池
Sea, Stove, White Pond, Blood Pond
鬼石坊主 鬼山 竜巻 どーん！
Shaven Head, Demon Mountain, Tornado! Boom!
とり天 とりめし やせうま だんご汁
Chicken tempura, chicken rice, yaseuma, dango soup
中津からあげ 冷麺 関アジ 関サバ
Nakatsu chicken, cold noodles, Seki Aji, Seki Saba
かぼす あつめし まだまだ入るよ
Kabosu, atsumeshi, I can still eat more
鉄の胃袋 大魔神
Iron stomach of a Great Demon God
行こうぜ 久住高原
Let's go to the Kuju Highlands
湯煙の温泉
To the steamy hot springs
高崎山に 金鱗湖
To Mount Takasaki and Lake Kinrin,
青の洞門 由布川渓谷
Ao-no-domon and Yufugawa Gorge,
進め 稲積水中鍾乳洞
onward, to Inazumi Underwater Limestone Cave!
果てしなき旅 一路奔走
An endless journey, running with all my might,
たどり着く先 食べる弁当
at the destination, I eat my bento.
時空を超えた奇跡の大地
A miracle land that transcends time and space,
バーチャル大分
Virtual Oita!
いくぞー！
Let's go!
バババ バーチャル大分 世に放つ
Ba-Ba-Ba, Virtual Oita, released to the world!
バババ バーチャル大分 湯を沸かす
Ba-Ba-Ba, Virtual Oita, boiling the hot springs!
君と バーチャル大分 駆け巡る
Running around Virtual Oita with you.
バババ バーチャル大分 大分 どーん！
Ba-Ba-Ba, Virtual Oita, Oita, Boom!
バババ バーチャル大分 世に放つ
Ba-Ba-Ba, Virtual Oita, released to the world!
バババ バーチャル大分 食べつくす
Ba-Ba-Ba, Virtual Oita, eat it all up!
君と バーチャル大分 駆け巡る
Running around Virtual Oita with you.
バババ バーチャル大分 大分 どーん！
Ba-Ba-Ba, Virtual Oita, Oita, Boom!
大分 どーん！
Oita, Boom!
よだきい
It's a hassle...
しゃあしぃ
You're noisy...
えらしい
Adorable...
しんけん
Seriously...
やあねえ
It's tough...
ふうがわり
Unusual...
なしか
Why?
むげねえ
So sad...
せせろしい
Restless...
だけどあんた今なにしちょん
But what are you doing now?
説明しよう。
Let me explain.
バーチャル大分観光大使とは バーチャル大分への深い郷土愛を持ち その魅力を伝え続ける存在。
Virtual Oita Tourism Ambassadors are those who love Virtual Oita and share its charms.
人はその大使の名を バーチャル大分観光大使と呼ぶ！
People call them Virtual Oita Tourism Ambassadors!
バーチャル O-O-I-T-A I wanna be バーチャル 団長 観光大使
Virtual O-O-I-T-A, I wanna be the Virtual Knight Leader Tourism Ambassador.
バーチャル O-O-I-T-A I wanna be バーチャル 団長 観光大使 (自称)
Virtual O-O-I-T-A, I wanna be the Virtual Knight Leader Tourism Ambassador (Self-proclaimed)!
バババ バーチャル大分 世に放つ
Ba-Ba-Ba, Virtual Oita, released to the world!
バババ バーチャル大分 湯を沸かす
Ba-Ba-Ba, Virtual Oita, boiling the hot springs!
君と バーチャル大分 駆け巡る
Running around Virtual Oita with you.
バババ バーチャル大分 大分 どーん！
Ba-Ba-Ba, Virtual Oita, Oita, Boom!
バババ バーチャル大分 世に放つ
Ba-Ba-Ba, Virtual Oita, released to the world!
バババ バーチャル大分 食べつくす
Ba-Ba-Ba, Virtual Oita, eat it all up!
君と バーチャル大分 駆け巡る
Running around Virtual Oita with you.
バババ バーチャル大分 大分 どーん！
Ba-Ba-Ba, Virtual Oita, Oita, Boom!
大分 どーん！
Oita, Boom!
団員さん！今年もお誕生日をお祝いしてくれて本当にありがとう～！！
Knights! Thank you so much for celebrating my birthday again this year!!
新衣装は表情など…どうだったかな？！
How did you like the expressions on my new outfit?!
少しでも好き～！ってなってもらえたらノエちゃんとっても嬉しいです✨
Noe-chan would be so happy if you liked it even a little bit!
来年も一緒に同じ時間を過ごせますように…🌸 大好きだよ～～🎵
I hope we can spend time together next year too... I love you!!